<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Can Holyavkin</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Can Holyavkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>tr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phylogenetic Analysis of SARS-CoV-2 Strains in Turkey</title>
      <link>/post/phylogenetic-analysis-of-sars-cov-2-strains-in-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/phylogenetic-analysis-of-sars-cov-2-strains-in-turkey/</guid>
      <description>As of May 2020, a total of 61 high coverage SARS-CoV-2 sequences were submitted to Global Initiative on Sharing All Influenza Data (GISAID) from Turkey. In this post, I’ll share an overview of the mutations and phylogenetic analysis of SARS-CoV-2 genomes in Turkey. Before analysis, I downloaded all sequences from GISAID, and performed multiple sequence alignment using MAFFT v7.450 tool.1 I constructed the phylogenetic tree using Phylip v.3.6 with Neighbor-Joining and composite likelihood method and 100 bootstrap replications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClinVar 2019 Overview</title>
      <link>/post/clinvar-2019-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/clinvar-2019-overview/</guid>
      <description>In 2018, Craig Venter and his team in Human Longevity Inc. published a remarkable article titled “Identification of Misclassified ClinVar Variants via Disease Population Prevalence”.1 The article was about excess genetic risk and misclassification in the ClinVar database. They observed that inflation increases as the level of evidence supporting the pathogenic nature of the variant decreases. In other words, variants that have fewer interpretation records were more prone to be misclassified as pathogenic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Million Song Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/the-million-song-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-million-song-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Dealing with R as a professional or hobby; you always need a good dataset to get started. The more comprehensive and interesting the dataset is, the more creative visuals and interesting statistical findings will be created. Unfortunately, finding such comprehensive and tidy data is not always easy. For this reason, I decided to start the ”Data Sources” series, which will introduce interesting datasets that you can access on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking on R</title>
      <link>/post/benchmarking-on-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/benchmarking-on-r/</guid>
      <description>The speed and performance analyzes that are performed to see how fast your function is or compare the faster one between the two functions is called benchmark tests. (In fact, benchmarking is called any kind of measurement and comparison process.) In this article, we’ll cover a few ways we can do a benchmark test in R.
At this point, you may want to consider why you need a performance test.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>